Pirates!
We're under attack!
Hold them off! Get down on the floor.
Tear gas!
What are you waiting for? Break it down!
Where'd she go?
There she is!
She's getting away!
Well get her!
Mama don't drop me!
There's the stone. Quick go next door!
Get that crystal!
There goes the crystal.
Castle in the Sky
Two meatballs please.
Working late?
We're finally busy again.
Still working?
Yeah.
What's that?
A person!
Pazu!
What are you up to? Where's my dinner?
Boss!
A girl fell from the sky.
Boss she fell from the sky...
Darn old clunker.
Boss! A girl...
Close Valve No. 2!
Ouch! Pazu toss me a wrench.
I'm busy here. You take it.
Don't make them wait.
Keep a steady hand.
Brake!
Any luck?
No silver no tin even.
All that wasted work.
Should we try the east vein?
That's riddled with old holes.
We'll have to start over.
That's enough for today.
Shut down the boiler. Call it a day.
I'll go under at this rate.
Oil the clunker Pazu.
Mama we couldn't find her. lt's too dark.
I hope you really looked!
All right. We'll wait for daylight.
Hi. How are you feeling? Hey come on guys...
I'm Pazu. I live here by myself.
They eat after I play.
So you are human after all.
I was afraid you were an angel.
Thanks for helping me. I'm Sheeta.
Sheeta nice name. You fell from the sky. A bit scary.
That's right. Why am I still alive?
I fell from the airship...
Don't you remember?
No.
Say can I see that?
This?
It's been in my family forever.
It's beautiful. Here...
Watch this!
Pazu!
So it wasn't the stone after all.
Oh no! Pazu!
Are you OK?
Yeah. Are you?
I'm fine. Sorry did it hurt?
No my head's harder than my boss's fists.
The pot's still boiling.
Hungry? Let's eat.
Wash up over there.
There's a towel.
Thank you.
Laputa...
Sheeta! Where are you?
My father took that picture.
That's Laputa an island in the sky.
An island in the sky...?
They say it's only a myth.
But my father saw it.
He took it from an airship.
There's a Laputa in Gulliver's Travels but Swift made it up.
Dad drew this.
He said the abandoned palace was full of treasure.
But nobody believed him.
Until he died they called him a liar.
But my father never lied.
I'm building a real plane. I'm going to find Laputa!
A real automobile... they're rare.
They're pirates!
They attacked the airship.
- Are they after you? - Yes.
Quick!
Morning!
Hey wait!
What? We're in a rush.
Have you seen a girl?
Sure yesterday... The boss's kid Madge...
Off you go!
They're indeed looking for you.
Louis a girl's dress!
What! She was disguised! Tell Mama!
Haven't seen her.
A cute little girl. Brown hair braids...
Boss!
About that age.
That's her!
Pirates! They're chasing her.
Pirates! Lemme see!
Not one step closer.
- Hand her over. - Pirates eh?
Dola's clan.
Go home. Just poor folk here.
Ma'am?
Scoot out the back.
I want to fight.
They've got weapons!
But...!
What a pretty girl. Better protect her.
You refuse to step aside?
Use your fists. Like a man.
Could be interesting.
Get him brother.
Show your stuff.
Wow.
Who's going to mend that shirt?
You can beat him!
That's it hit him!
Think you can fool me? After them!
Yes!
Climb on!
There you go.
Playing hooky for a date?
Bad guys are after us.
The Dola clan.
Pirates?
Take us to the next town. To the police!
You're on. Stoke the fire.
Right!
Mama!
You idiots! Hurry up and get on!
What? But the girl's...
She slipped out the back door.
Get moving!
Brother!
Wait!
They're catching up more steam!
Can't you go any faster?
She's an old-timer.
Move over!
Mama I can't hang on!
More steam they're gaining on us!
Here we go!
Sheeta over here.
Stoke the fire.
Don't give up!
Push! Push I tell you!
Not so fast!
Don't let them escape! Dump this over the side!
That'll teach them!
I'll do it.
No let me.
Wait!
It's them. What'll we do?
I refuse to give up. Move!
This is a surprise. If it isn't the army.
These kids need help! They've got pirates after them.
Sheeta?
Goodbye.
Wait!
Sheeta!
Halt or l'll shoot.
An armored train.
Who cares! Ram it!
What is it Sheeta!
Stay away!
They're gonna fall!
Quiet. Watch closely.
We're floating!
Look! It's that crystal!
It was the stone after all! Amazing!
We'll float all the way down.
Amazing! I want it!
Fire!
I have to get that amazing stone!
It's fading...
Hey wait!
It's just like when you landed.
The opening looks so tiny.
I hope the Boss and the engineer aren't in any trouble.
Aw don't worry. Miners aren't exactly wimps.
Come on let's find the way out.
These mines are ancient. Tunnels everywhere.
There.
I'm so happy. I was starving.
I've still got an apple and some candy.
It's like you have a magical bag that holds everything.
Gondoa? That's so far north.
Yes. Both my parents died but they left me the house and the fields
so I was getting by alone.
The guys with dark glasses kidnapped you?
Yes.
That guy was one of them?
Who can they be calling in the army?
Dola and the other guys they all want the stone.
But I had no idea it had mysterious powers.
It was always in our family. Mother left it to me when she died.
She warned me never to show it or give it to anyone.
We're both orphans aren't we?
I'm sorry I dragged you into all of this.
When you fell from the sky my heart was racing.
I knew something wonderful had begun.
Little demons... little demons.
Uncle Pom! It's OK. He's really great.
Uncle Pom.
We've lost our way.
Now that little demon sure looks like Pazu...
With a little girl demon beside him.
Pirates are after us.
And the army.
How very extraordinary.
Drink up.
Thank you.
Have you always lived underground?
Why no no. The rocks have been stirring...
That's when I like to be down here.
The rocks were stirring...?
Rocks speak very softly.
Wonderful...
Pazu look at that!
They were ordinary rocks until...
How pretty...
Here let me show you.
It's gone.
These rocks contain Volucite.
Volucite?
As soon as it's exposed to the air it becomes ordinary stone.
It's glowing...
Oh my gracious! That's a Volucite crystal my dear.
I've never seen one before.
That's why the rocks were stirring.
This stone has mysterious powers.
I thought only Laputans knew how to make Volucite crystals.
Laputans...?
They used Volucite to send a magnificent island aloft...
Laputa did exist Sheeta! It really did!
Does the island still exist?
Uncle Pom?
Dear would you mind covering the stone? Its power overwhelms me.
What's wrong?
My grandfather told me...
that the rocks stir when Laputa floats overhead.
If you went up to the sky then you'd find Laputa!
Sheeta my father was telling the truth!
Young lady...
Well...
Yes?
Your stone is most powerful...
I know it as one who has spoken to rocks all my life.
A stone so powerful brings happiness but it also often brings misery.
What's more your stone is the work of men.
How on earth did you...?
The stone's not dangerous!
It already saved Sheeta twice!
Amazing! Laputa really does exist!
It's gone.
Let's go back to the ship.
When it's this quiet it's best to stay put.
I'm hungry...
It's all clear. Let's go.
Thank you Uncle.
Look after yourselves.
Look at those clouds!
Beyond those clouds is an island we've only dreamed of.
Here I come! I know I'm going to find Laputa!
Pazu...
I haven't told you everything.
My family had a mysterious ancient name...
that came with this stone.
My name is Lucita Lucita Toelle Ur....
Laputa.
Laputa?
So you mean...
It's the army! Run!
Underground!
Don't move!
How dare you!
Pazu! Let me go!
Pazu! Pazu!
We've apprehended them.
Good work.
Open up open up!
Sheeta...
Company march!
Use force!
Squeeze the brat she'll talk.
Spoken like a man in uniform.
In your haste you risk everything.
If we'd mobilized sooner we'd have bagged Dola too.
She managed to decipher your third-rate code.
What!
My organization will handle this.
Concentrate on mobilizing the troops when the time is ripe.
Muska! Remember I command the search for Laputa!
Of course. But I have my orders from the government.
That pencil-pushing upstart!
Have a nice rest?
Where's Pazu? Let me see him!
No interest in pretty clothes?
Don't fret about Pazu. His stubborn head is harder than mine.
Come I have something to show you.
Enter.
What is it?
A mechanical soldier with vast destructive power.
Until he fell from the sky no one believed Laputa was real.
He's not of this earth.
Our science can't even identify...
what material he's made of.
Look... Don't be afraid.
He's long dead.
Look at that.
This insignia was carved on your fireplace.
It's on this stone too.
The stone works only in your hands.
It protects its owner and will guide her back to Laputa.
I know nothing of this!
Take it if you like. Just leave us alone...
Perhaps you imagine that Laputa is some Treasure Island.
Fearsome scientific power thrust Laputa into orbit.
Their dreaded empire once ruled the earth!
Even you can appreciate that when such an entity...
roams the skies it threatens peace.
I need your cooperation.
You must know how to make the stone guide us to Laputa.
I really don't know! Please let me see Pazu!
I intend no harm but his fate rests with you.
The boy goes free if you assist us Lucita...
Toelle Ur Laputa.
But how...?
Ur means ruler. Toelle means True.
You are Queen Lucita rightful heir to the Laputan throne.
Out!
Sheeta!
Pazu are you hurt?
I'm fine. You? Did they do anything horrible?
My dear Pazu we misjudged you. Accept our apologies.
We didn't know how gallantly...
you protected her from the pirates.
Sheeta what did you...
Pazu I beg you forget about Laputa.
What!
Sheeta will aid us in our search for Laputa.
I understand how you feel but forget about her.
Is this true Sheeta? But we...
Thank you for everything.
I'll never forget you Pazu.
I don't believe it...
Sheeta we promised!
Farewell!
Sheeta!
Wait Sheeta!
Be reasonable. Act like a man.
Sheeta!
Here's a token of our gratitude. It's yours.
Only you can recall the words that will waken this stone.
If you keep your promise you too shall be free.
Pazu...
Mama it's Pazu! He's back!
Pazu.
We were so worried. You just disappeared.
And the girl?
Forget it.
Pazu!
Let me go! What are you doing!
Put a lid on it!
Nice place you got kid.
Get out!
This is my house!
Oh come off it.
Can't even protect a little girl...
What?
He's got gold!
Sold her for money huh?
No! I wouldn't do that!
You let them pay you off?
Sheeta told me to do it.
So...
So you gave in and crawled home.
You call yourself a man?
You talk big but you're after Sheeta too.
But of course we're pirates. Pirates hunt for treasure.
Those guys are strange ones. What's the girl to them?
You think she'll get out alive?
So Sheeta told you to leave?
They threatened her so she tried to save you.
How do you know Mama?
I've been a woman for 50 years.
She steels her heart to save her man. How touching.
Reminds me of my youth.
You boys want to marry look for one like her.
- So that girl will grow up... - To be like Mama?
What a waste.
I've got all your codes.
Calling the battle cruiser...?
They'll pack her up and take off? We better hurry!
Dinner's over. Move out.
Yes Mama.
Going after Sheeta?
We want the crystal not the girl.
The stone's no good without her.
Can't I go with you?
I have to help Sheeta!
Do it on your own like a man.
You're right if I was clever and strong I could've defended her.
Please I don't care about treasure.
Listen to him...
Shut up!
Right...
He could probably help us with her...
You'll be an outcast forever.
I know.
You sure?
Yup!
Be ready in 40 seconds.
Take care you guys.
Tie this to your belt. You boys wait on the ship.
A magnificent vessel. Has the girl talked?
I need a little more time.
Forget it! We'll squeeze it out of her up there.
We depart at dawn with the girl.
Step on it it's almost dawn!
Sheeta!
Whatever shall we do?
Sheeta listen I'm going to teach you...
a magic spell for trouble.
A magic spell?
Yes. These are old old old secret words.
They mean help me rekindle the light.
Perfect.
Just as the ancient books described. This is the sacred light.
Sacred light...?
What are the magic words? Tell me.
It's moving!
The robot it's alive!
Hello!
Help!
It's alive! It's the robot!
The robot?
It's coming this way.
Hurry!
Retreat! Retreat!
Incredible!
I see!
It's the light!
The sacred light broke his seal!
The way to Laputa is open! Come!
No!
It can fly!
It's pointing to the sky...
It's showing the way to Laputa.
Hurry!
Explosives? Idiot! You'll blow up the fortress!
Hello hello! What is this!
Good.
We're connected.
This is Colonel Muska. The robot cut communication with the ship.
I've assumed emergency command.
It's after the girl on the tower.
Take it down on sight.
Prepare to fire. Just don't hit the girl.
Hurry! Hurry up!
Fire!
Hurry!
We did it. Awesome!
Get the girl.
Is she dead?
Get up!
She just fainted.
Stand!
It moved...
What's that? Looks like a war.
Let's go granny!
That's Captain to you!
Lower Charles.
Stop! Stop it!
Please!
Mama Goliath's pushing off!
We're going directly into the crossfire. Regroup!
Look there's Sheeta!
What?
Where?
Straight ahead she's on top of that tower!
This is a job for a woman! Cover me.
Sheeta!
I'm coming Sheeta!
Pazu!
Fly closer!
Let me go!
Sheeta!
Granny!
Pazu!
Pull up!
Last chance! Grab her on the fly!
Pazu!
Here goes!
Move aside!
Damn!
Sheeta!
What's Goliath doing?
A smoke screen...?
Where's the robot?
Destroyed. The girl went that way.
What!
Put out the fire! Organize a search party!
We haven't lost the sacred stone.
Its light points to Laputa...
Inform the General we'll depart for Laputa as planned.
He's lucky...
I can't believe she'll grow up to be just like Mama...
There's your valley... Right back where we started.
Granny please take us aboard.
Call me Captain! What use are you without the crystal?
We'll work.
I want to see Laputa for myself.
Don't want any treasure just want to see Laputa?
Suspect motives for boarding a pirate ship.
Are they coming with us Mama?
One false move and you're shark bait!
Excellent! No more laundry or cleaning duty!
Or dish washing!
Or potato peeling!
Can you make pudding?
Yes...
I like mincemeat pie.
I eat uhm... anything!
Enough out of you!
When will those boys ever grow up?
Get off!
Cloth. It's made of cloth.
And don't tear it.
Hurry up it's crowded in here!
Hurry this way!
I hate dawdlers.
You're with me!
Pazu!
I don't bite. Come.
You're not here for fun.
What an engine.
Now where'd he go? Pops! Pops!
Look we got you an assistant.
Don't holler. I hear you.
He's tougher than Mama. Be careful.
My hand doesn't fit.
This gasket?
Name?
Pazu.
The crystal pointed nearly due east...
You sure about that?
I could see the sunrise from the tower. It's the harvest season now...
so the sun rises just south of due east.
The light pointed to the left of where the sun rose.
Good answer. Any luck?
Not a peep.
Maintaining radio silence are they?
Mama Goliath's faster. What do we do?
We're upwind of them. If we get a lift on the trade winds...
My Far East-style calculator.
Windspeed is 10... and...
I think we can catch them.
OK listen up!
Goliath's on its way to Laputa. We're on their tail.
With these winds I expect contact tomorrow.
Ten gold pieces to whoever spots her first!
Ten!
Whatever we find I'm sure Laputa has riches enough for any pirate gang!
Earn your keep boys!
Now!
Course 98 speed 40.
That get-up of yours won't work.
Wear these.
Your station.
Beautiful...
You serve five meals a day. Go easy on the water.
Get to work you idiots!
Yes?
I'm sorry dinner isn't ready yet.
I've never cooked on an airship...
Do you need something?
Beautiful...
I thought I'd give you a hand in my spare time.
Why thank you. Can you put those dishes away?
Happy to obli...
You said your stomach hurt...
I've got some free time. Can I...
You're in the way.
Some stomach ache jerk!
Hey can I help...
You've changed chasing the likes of Goliath... But it's pointless.
It's Laputan treasure I'm after.
They're certainly nice kids...
Get to the point you old goat.
They're too upright and honest to ever respect you.
What's that!
No I mean... Check...
Excellent... delicious...
Seconds anyone?
Yes?
Seconds! Seconds! Seconds!
Hey shake a leg.
It's your watch.
Take it it's cold.
Watch?
Yeah.
Darn cold! Go on up.
My turn.
Great.
Sheeta!
That was scary!
It's beautiful.
Sheeta. Get in.
Can't you sleep?
Nice and warm...
Look aft.
Pazu?
I'm really scared.
I really don't want to go to Laputa.
I hope we never find Goliath.
You mean...?
No the light showed the right way. But...
You mean the robot?
Poor thing.
I never dreamed that little spell would work.
I learned lots of other spells.
To help find things cure the sick. And one I must never ever use.
Never ever use...?
A spell of destruction.
I had to learn bad ones so the good spells had power.
I was so scared I couldn't sleep.
That stone should be locked away.
They hid it in the fireplace. It was only worn for weddings.
My mother's and grandmother's and great grandmother's.
I should have thrown it away.
You're wrong. We met because of the stone.
Throwing it away won't make Laputa disappear.
Airships are improving. Someone will find it.
I don't know what to do but if Laputa is so dangerous...
it's not for the likes of Muska.
Besides...
If we run now they'll hunt us forever.
But don't become a pirate for me.
I won't become a pirate.
Dola understands. She's nicer than she looks.
Once things are settled I'll take you to Gondoa.
I want to see where you were born the valley the yaks...
Pazu...
What's that!
Below us look!
Goliath right below us!
Come about! Full rudder!
We should go after them. They'll be trouble if we don't!
We can't catch them in these clouds.
We'll get them. They won't go far.
Steady as she goes.
We're farther north than I thought.
Pazu listen up! Time's running out.
If we lose Goliath it's all over. Your eyes are sharp.
Track them from the crow's nest.
What do I do?
That lookout post is a glider. See the crank?
Yeah.
Turn it clockwise.
Once it's locked the upper lever unfolds the wings.
Use the wire to stabilize them. Figure out how to steer as you go!
- Sheeta you there? - Yes.
Get back down here.
Why?
Because you're a girl!
But so are you! Besides I'm a mountain girl with sharp eyes.
Sheeta!
Please. Pazu agrees.
Once you're aloft the voice tube won't work. See the head set?
You mean this right?
Wow...
OK. I'll give it a try. Release us.
Here goes.
They're gone.
Slipped into the clouds.
Look sharp! They could be anywhere.
Aye!
Hold on tight.
What's wrong!
We're fine!
Just ran into a gust of wind.
We're keeping watch.
Scared?
No.
I'm getting the hang of it. Rough skies ahead.
Sheeta get the rope from my bag.
Tie yourself to me.
The mercury's dropping Mama...
Lousy luck. Storm coming up... How long 'til dawn?
One more hour.
It's dawn.
Strange that the sun's rising on that side...
I know! We're supposed to be heading east. Bridge!
What! We're heading north?
The compass is pointing east.
The shifting winds must have put us off course.
Look!
What is it? Goliath?
It's a cloud. A huge one...
A cloud?
It's headed for us!
A castle in the sky...
We're headed into a low pressure system.
Turn her away full speed!
It's sucking us in.
Hold tight we can't help!
The helm won't move!
Where's your brute strength?
Hey!
Engine's burning up!
Stop whining and figure something out!
We're clearing the clouds!
Sheeta the ocean!
The Dragon's Lair!
So this is the Dragon's Lair...
Just as Dad said. The wind's blowing the other way.
Look out a wall of wind!
Mama! It's sucking us in!
Don't give up! Be a man!
Bridge! It's Laputa!
What was that!
Dad saw Laputa inside the Dragon's Lair.
Don't be ridiculous! It'll tear you to pieces!
Pazu!
Look.
Just what we need.
Let's go for it! Dad did it. He made it back.
All right into the Dragon's Lair!
Got 'em!
Our ship's in danger. We must withdraw.
Stay on course.
The light's pointing right into the cloud.
Laputa's in there.
Stay on course. We'll find a way in.
Here we go Sheeta!
Sheeta Sheeta! Are you all right?
Look...
Laputa...?
Oops.
Wait... I tied it really tight.
My hands are shaking...
We did it!
Birds...
Where is everyone?
Coming to greet you?
But I don't have the stone.
I'll cut the rope.
What are you doing!
Wait.
Please don't break that. We need it to get home.
A flycatcher's nest!
That's why he's here?
See? All your eggs are fine.
The birds aren't afraid.
It says to follow.
- You understand it? - Just intuition.
It's a city...
What an amazing place...
You can see the sky!
If their science was so advanced what happened?
It's a grave. I wish I could read the writing.
Someone left flowers.
Do you put these here?
Pazu!
It's a different robot!
It must've broken down long ago...
Probably a gardener robot.
It protected this place even after the people went away.
You picked flowers for the grave?
Thank you.
Are you all alone? Are there any other robots here?
He doesn't seem to be lonely.
He's got friends and birds' nests to look after...
This way!
This section's been destroyed.
They got the Tiger Moth.
I hope the pirates are OK.
Sheeta look there!
They're prisoners!
They hang pirates.
We must help them.
Let's go!
We found a way in.
Look at this mountains of treasure.
Wow...
Want some?
I'll give you plenty of rope.
Have you reported that we found Laputa?
Just about to.
Make the code good and complicated.
Hey! No looting!
The perfect distraction for those idiots.
What amazing roots.
You can climb trees can't you?
I see a way.
No better than thieves.
If they reach the garden...!
Sheeta let's find the stone!
It's the only way to stop them.
I was wondering why the clouds parted.
It was so they could land.
Was it my spell...?
Muska was right. The seal's broken.
The kingdom's waking up.
It's welcomed the visitor with the stone.
But Muska will become king.
He's got much worse in mind.
But what do I do when I get the stone back...
That spell!
You mean... the destruction spell?
Down and around.
I'll go first.
It's here somewhere.
Please God...
This is it!
It's that kid.
No!
Don't shoot! Capture her.
Well if it isn't the little princess.
Sheeta! Damn!
What is it Colonel?
The last of the pirates. There's one right under you.
Yes sir!
Sheeta wait for me!
Pazu!
Grenades!
Is that Pazu?
What was that?
No it wasn't.
The General is over there.
Militia fall in on the double.
Granny!
They've got Sheeta.
I'm going after her. I'll cut your ropes.
Get out of here.
Hey wait!
Take this.
Thanks.
The boy has become a man.
What?!
Muska destroyed all the radio equipment?
Yes while the ship was lightly guarded.
Several guards are badly wounded.
The Colonel entered the inner palace with the girl.
The soldiers saw him.
That upstart's finally showing his colors.
Hunt him down and arrest him!
All units!
Hey! Hurry!
Shoot if he resists!
Find the entrance.
Where are we Colonel?
Laputa's core. The castle above is just a trifle.
All of Laputa's knowledge is crystallized here.
You two wait here.
Colonel!
Only royalty may enter the sacred area.
What is this!
The roots have invaded...
Eventually we'll burn them all.
Come this way.
Confound it...
Yes...
This is it!
Here too!
Curse it...
Found it!
Behold the giant crystal! Source of Laputa's power.
Fantastic. It has awaited the king's return for 700 years.
700 years?
Your family forgot even that?
The black rock! As the epics described!
I can read it. I know what it says!
Just who are you?
I too have an ancient secret name Lucita.
My name is Romuska Palo Ur Laputa.
We are descended from the same royal family.
Later it split into two branches.
Not even a crack.
It's indestructible.
Deploy all our explosives.
Force won't be necessary Your Excellency.
Muska where are you!
What are you waiting for General?
All right after me!
Forward!
What is this! Muska where are you?
Silence!
What on earth!
Watch your tongue. You're in the presence of Laputa's king.
Are you insane?
Let's celebrate Laputa's return with a demonstration of its power.
Sheeta!
Behold Laputa's thunder!
Sheeta.
It's the heavenly fire that destroyed Sodom and Gomorrah.
It's the Ramayana's Arrow of Indra.
The world shall bow down before Laputa once more!
Wonderful Muska. You're a hero. A monumental achievement.
I grow tired of your stupid face.
Run everyone!
Die!
- It's those monsters! - Look at them...
Run!
Are the Flaptors OK?
Ready to fly!
Let's hurry!
Quiet. Keep your voice down.
What are those two doing? I'll have to leave them behind.
I advise you not to anger me.
We'll be alone here for a long time.
They should've escaped.
You think you can fight me?
Robots!
Sheeta!
Fantastic!
A marvelous display no?
Die you insects!
How dare you!
Damn!
Be a good girl give it back.
Please open!
Just where will you go?
Open!
Sheeta!
Pazu!
I'm coming.
Get back!
Take this hurry! Muska's coming quick!
Throw it into the sea.
Hold onto that stone. I'll trade her life for it.
Get up! No more hide and seek.
How delightful that it should end in the throne room. Come here!
The throne room? This will be our grave.
What is a king when his country lies ruined?
I won't give you the stone.
You'll die trapped here with me. There's no escape.
This is why Laputa died out.
There's a song in my valley... Put down your roots in the soil...
Live together with the wind.
Pass the winter with the seeds sing in the spring with the birds...
Your weapons may be powerful. Your pitiful robots may be many.
But you can't survive apart from the earth.
Laputa will not die. It will rise again.
Its power is the stuff of humanity's dreams.
Next I shoot off your ears!
Beg for your life. Make the kid hand over the stone.
Wait!
The stone's hidden. You can shoot but you won't get it.
Stay away Pazu. He'll kill us both.
I'll spare her life if you tell me where the stone is.
Or do you intend to conquer me with that cannon of yours?
Let me talk to Sheeta alone.
Run away. Take the stone and run!
Three minutes.
Sheeta calm down and listen. Teach me that spell.
I'll say it with you.
Put your hand in mine.
I cut the pirates' ropes.
Time's up. What do you say?
My eyes! My eyes!
I can't see...
Mama it's collapsing!
All right let's go. Hurry!
Hurry!
Look the bottom's falling out!
Sheeta was such a nice girl...
They used the spell of destruction.
Those kids saved Laputa from those idiots.
It's stopping!
A crystal! A humongous one!
It's rising.
The tree... it's carrying it away. Chase it!
You're heavy get off.
I can't!
Sheeta.
Pazu...
The roots protected us.
We can still use this.
Here goes.
What are you doing? We're not moving.
Of course not we're overloaded.
It's Sheeta!
She's alive!
It's them!
Granny!
Thank God you're alive!
You guys OK?
We're not! My galleon's wrecked...
Oh stop blubbering. We'll build a better ship!
You poor child the worst is having your hair hacked off...
- I can't breathe! - Sorry.
Pathetic. All that work and only this to show.
We ran out of time!
ano chiheisen kagayaku no wa The reason the horizon shines
doko ka ni kimi o kakushite iru kara is that somewhere it's hiding you.
taku-san no hi ga natsukashii no wa The reason I long for the many lights
ano dore ka hitotsu ni is that you are there
kimi ga iru kara in one of them.
saa dekake you So I set out
hitokire no pan with a slice of bread
naifu rampu kaban ni tsume konde a knife a lamp stuffed in a bag.
tousan ga nokoshita atsui omoi Father left me his burning desire.
kaasan ga kureta ano manazashi Mother gave me her eyes.
chikyuu wa mawaru kimi o kakushite The earth turns hiding you.
kagayaku hitomi kirameku tomoshibi Shining eyes twinkling lights.
chikyuu wa mawaru kimi o nosete The earth turns carrying you
itsuka kitto deau bokura o nosete carrying us both who'll surely meet.
tousan ga nokoshita atsui omoi Father left me his burning desire.
kaasan ga kureta ano manazashi Mother gave me her eyes.
chikyuu wa mawaru kimi o kakushite The earth turns hiding you.
kagayaku hitomi kirameku tomoshibi Shining eyes twinkling lights.
chikyuu wa mawaru kimi o nosete The earth turns carrying you
itsuka kitto deau bokura o nosete carrying us both who'll surely meet.